The verdict came down: This Melusine is guilty
Gereği düşünüldü: Melusina suçlu.
The Iudex defended the authority of Fontaine law
Iudex, Fontaine hukukunun otoritesini korudu
But he did not confiscate the Melusine's medical kit
ancak Melusinanın tıbbi malzemelerine el koymadı.
And so, the Fortress of Meropide gained a new little doctor
Böylece Meropide Kalesi'nin yeni bir doktoru olmuş oldu.
She still wore her hood and raincoat
Kalede hiç yağmur yağmasa da
Even though it never rained in the Fortress
hâlâ kapüşonunu ve yağmurluğunu giymeye devam ediyordu.
Perhaps thanks to her human appearance, no one refused her treatment
Belki de insan görünümü sayesinde kimse onun tedavisini reddetmedi.
She treated more and more patients, and her sentence grew ever shorter
Gittikçe daha fazla hastaya şifa oldu ve cezası da kısaldı.
Finally, the people of the Fortress could not live without her
Sonunda Kaledeki insanlar onsuz yaşayamayacak hale gelmişti
And though her sentence ended, she did not leave them either
ve o da cezası bitmesine rağmen orada kalmayı seçti.
Then one day, she received an invitation from the outside world
Sonra bir gün, dış dünyadan bir davetiye aldı.
The location seemed familiar, and when she arrived, an old lady was waiting for her
Bu yer tanıdık gelmişti ve vardığında yaşlı bir kadın onu bekliyordu.
She saw right through the Melusine's disguise, but didn't reveal it
Melusinanın farklı bir kılıkta olduğunu hemen anladı ama açık etmedi.
Instead, she asked a question
Onun yerine şu soruyu sordu:
Tell me, why do you think you gained the respect of so many people
Söylesene, sence neden bu kadar çok insanın saygısını kazandın?
Despite being a Melusine?
Hem de bir Melusina olmana rağmen.
Because... I look like a human?
İnsanlara benzediğim için mi?
It's been fifty years, Sigewinne
Elli yıl geçti Sigewinne,
And you haven't aged a day...
biraz olsun yaşlanmadın... Bence herkes senin insan olmadığının farkında.
I've finally found you, after all these years
Bunca yılın ardından nihayet seni buldum.
I still remember, you know. It was you who saved me that night
Hâlâ hatırlıyorum biliyor musun? O gece beni sen kurtardın.
But how? I was no longer a Melusine by then
Ama nasıl? O zaman Melusina değildim ki.
Does it really matter if you're human or Melusine?
İnsan ya da Melusina olman fark eder mi gerçekten?
I remembered the warmth of your palm
Avucunun sıcaklığından anlamıştım.
It's quite unmistakable
Bu çok belliydi.
And you know what? It hasn't changed one bit
Ve biliyor musun? Biraz bile değişmemiş.
You don't have to hide anymore, Sigewinne
Artık gizlenmene gerek yok Sigewinne.
These days, everyone wants to make friends with Melusines
Şimdilerde herkes bir Melusinayla arkadaş olmak istiyor
And I think that it's all because of you
ve bence hepsi senin sayende.
I'm sorry I couldn't say this until now, but...
Şimdiye kadar söyleme fırsatım olmadı ama...
Thank you, Doctor Melusine
Teşekkürler Doktor Melusina!